raptitude.com 2018-12-30

# Privacy policy and disclaimer

Your privacy is important to me. Where user privacy is concerned I have a few fundamental principles:

I don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop my products, or protect my rights.

I do not sell user information.

I don’t store personal information on my host’s servers unless required for the ongoing operation of this website or one of its services.

In my blog and its products, I aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what’s visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted. You can contact me any time via the contact form if you have any questions about the site or its policies.

Raptitude.com officially operates under a small company called Snow City Media, which will hereafter in this document be referred to as “SCM.” It is SCM’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information it may collect while operating this website and other websites that operate under SCM. At this time raptitude.com is the only website that operates under SCM.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, SCM collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. SCM’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how SCM visitors use its websites. From time to time, SCM may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, for example by publishing a post on trends in the usage of its website.

SCM also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments. SCM only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrator of the site where the comment was left.

SCM may make use of third-party services that may make use of personal information including but not limited to email addresses, IP addresses and other non-personally identifying information. SCM cannot oversee or be held liable for third party usage of such information.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to SCM’s websites choose to interact with SCM in ways that require SCM to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that SCM gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. Those who engage in transactions with SCM – by purchasing products or services, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, SCM collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with SCM. SCM does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. Visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act

COPPA is a US law that restricts how websites (somehow, even non-US websites) can collect information about children. According to the FTC, “The Rule applies to operators of commercial websites and online services directed to children under 13 that collect, use, or disclose personal information from children, and operators of general audience websites or online services with actual knowledge that they are collecting, using, or disclosing personal information from children under 13.”

SCM does not operate websites directed to children under 13 and does not collect, use or disclose personal information from visitors known to be under 13.

### Aggregated Statistics

SCM may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, SCM may monitor inbound traffic sources, visitor time spent online, bounce rate etc. SCM may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, SCM does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

SCM discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on SCM’s behalf or to provide services available at SCM’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using SCM’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. SCM will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, SCM discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when SCM believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of SCM, third parties or the public at large. If you are a subscriber of a SCM website and have supplied your email address, SCM may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with SCM and our products. I primarily use posts on raptitude.com to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. SCM takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. SCM uses cookies to help it identify and track visitors, their usage of SCM websites, and their website access preferences. SCM visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using SCM’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of SCM’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Business Transfers

If SCM, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that SCM goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of SCM may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by SCM and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Comments

Comments contributed by visitors to SCM’s websites, including all information supplied in the comment form including Name (as supplied by the visitor) and Website are visible to all other visitors and are stored on the server indefinitely. An email address is also necessary to leave a comment and is stored by the blogging software but it is not visible to visitors. It is not required to be a valid email address, and will never be given away or sold or added to mailing lists without permission, or used for any reason except for the administrator to contact the commenting visitor. This seldom happens and usually only happens when you are a regular commenter I believe you would actually want to hear from me, and I don’t have a better way of contacting you, for example if I wanted to ask a question about the book you recommended in your comment. Still, SCM reserves the right to do so for any reason.

### Correspondence sent via contact form

Raptitude.com has a contact form that website visitors may use to get in touch with me. This content may be published on the blog, with personally-identifying information removed. I will almost always ask permission before doing so, but reserve the right to publish non-personally-identifying content copied from inbound contact form emails without the user’s permission, in the event that I believe it has value to other visitors of SCM’s websites. If the visitor requests beforehand that it not be published, or expressly denies permission beforehand when asked, it will not be published.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, SCM may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in SCM’s sole discretion. SCM encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

This Privacy Policy was adapted from that of [Automattic.com](http://automattic.com/) via Creative Commons Sharealike license. You are free to use it too, as long as you offer your resulting policy under Creative Commons Sharealike license, and maybe link to Automattic.com because it was cool of them to offer it for others to use it as a framework.

All content provided on this site is for informational purposes only. Please note that raptitude.com and its parent company Snow City Media has financial relationships with some of the merchants and website proprietors mentioned on this blog. But I do not engage in disingenuous endorsement. If I say I like something, I really do. If I say something is worthwhile, I really think it is. Raptitude.com makes no guarantees as to accuracy, completeness or relevance of any claims made on this site and will not be held liable for any errors or omissions in their content, or any losses, injuries, damages or misunderstandings arising from the publication or use of this site’s content. All information and advice is the opinion of the giver, whether it is that of the proprietor of the site or that of a visitor. Do with it what you will and take responsibility for it.

***

Snow City Media  
43 Osborne Street  
PO Box 68001 Osborne Village  
Winnipeg, MB R3L 2V9
